Guide to the Evan Rupert Nash Collection, 1827-1945
Department of Special Collections
Evan Rupert Nash Collection,
1827-1945
Special Collections M0127
Nash, Evan Rupert.
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Evan R. Nash, 1965.
Scope and Content
Letters primarily to or by members of the Nash family about their lives in the Oneida and Wallingford Communities, their work, activities and beliefs. A lot of geneological material on the Nash and Poole families. Excellent Civil War letters from Edwin S. Nash and a few by David Watson Knowles. Describes the life of an ordinary soldier and several important battles including Fredericksburg, Chancellorsville, Gettysburg and The Wilderness. 1827 - 1945 and a number of undated items.
Biographical Note
The NASH Family and its Name
The name of Nash is of Saxon origin and was probably originally Atte-an-ash, referring to the place of residence of the person to whom it was applied, and gradually became At-n-ash, At-Nash, and finally Nash. It is sometimes found on ancient records in the additional forms of Nashe and Naish.
The family, like its name, was of Saxon origin and was resident in England long prior to the time of the Norman conquest of England by William the Conqueror in 1066. It was to be found at early dates in the counties of Oxford, Worcester, London, Suffolk, and Lancaster, as well as in Ulster, Ireland, and in Wales, about the end of the sixteenth century. It is thought probable that the root stock of the family was the line of Oxfordshire. This line was represented in the early sixteenth century by one John Nash, who was the father of Michael Nash, who was living in the year 1574.
Of the Worcestershire line, probably a branch of the County Oxford family, one Richard Nash was succeeded in the early seventeenth century by his brother Dr. Treadway Russell Nash, who was succeeded by his only child Margaret, who married John, first Earl Somers. The estates of this line later reverted to the descendants of the younger branches of the family in Worcester.
One family of the name was early situated in London and from this line was descended the Nash who became Lord Mayor of London in 1772.
Of the Lancaster line of the family, one Edward Nash was living in 1592 and was the father of at least two sons, Edward and John, of whom the first emigrated to New England about 1649 and will be mentioned again later, and the second is believed to have gone to Virginia and been the ancestor of the family of that colony and of the branch which was later to be found in the colony of North Carolina.
It is thought that the first of the Nashes to emigrate to New England was James Nash, who made his home at Weymouth, Mass., in 1628. He was the father of James and Jacob Nash and probably of others as well.
In 1630 one Gregory Nash emigrated from England to Charlestown, Mass., in the fleet with Winthrop. He and his wife both died shortly after, leaving a son named William, who was the father by his wife Mary of several children, among whom were Peter and Mary.
Thomas Nash, who emigrated in 1637 from Lancaster, England, to Boston, Mass., is believed to have been the progenitor of the most numerous of the families of the name in America. He brought with him his wife Margery Baker and their children, Mary, John, Sarah, Joseph, and Timothy.
About 1649 Edward Nash, before mentioned emigrant from the county of Lancaster, made his home at Stratford, Conn., and later removed to Norwalk, in the same colony. It is probable that he was related in some way to the emigrant Thomas last mentioned. His children were Ann, Hannah, and John and there may have been others but no further record has been found.
Joshua Nash of Boston prior to 1659, in which year he married Elizabeth Porter, was the father of five children, Thomas, Elizabeth, Sarah, Robert, and Joseph.
One John Nash was living in Boston about the same time and is believed to have been the younger brother of Joshua. He married Rebecca Smith sometime before 1667 and was the father by her of Mary and John, and possibly of others.
Sometime before the year 1670 a Joseph Nash emigrated to New England and is said to have been first at Scituate, then at Weymouth, and finally at Boston, in the colony of Massachusetts. By his wife Elizabeth Holbrook he is known to have had one son named Joseph and probably had others, but no further record of his family is at hand.
Francis Nash of Braintree, Mass., is recorded as serving in King Phillip's War in 1675 and is believed to have emigrated quite a time before or perhaps to have descended from one of the earlier branches of the family in America. By his first wife Elizabeth he had issue of Elizabeth, Samuel, Thomas, John, Margaret, and another child that died in early youth. In 1697 he married as his second wife Mary (Purchas) Niles, a widow, and had further issue of Benjamin, James, and Mary.
Others of the family who emigrated during the seventeenth century but left few records of themselves and their families were Samuel of Plymouth in 1630, who is known to have had two daughters, one of whom was named Martha; Robert of Boston in 1643, who had been previously at Charlestown; Isaac of Dover in 1657, who later removed to York, Me., and is known to have had a wife named Phebe; John of Salisbury in 1660, who had been earlier at Newbury; and one William, whose date of emigration is not known, but who was living in Virginia before 1700.
Many others of the name emigrated to America in the following century, among whom was the family of another William Nash, who settled at Bedminster, Pa. Some authorities claim that he was of German ancestry but this is not certain. He was the father of nine children, Elise, Ann, Katharine, Magdalena, William, Elizabeth, Joseph, Benjamin, and Abraham, by three wives whose maiden names are not known.
The descendants of these various branches of the family in America have spread to practically every State of the Union and have aided as much in the growth of the country as their ancestors aided in the founding of the nation. They have been noted for their courage, energy, ambition, industry, piety, integrity, power of will, hatred of hypocrisy, resourcefulness, mental ability, and leadership.
Among those of the Nashes who fought as officers in the War of the Revolution were Captain Clement of North Carolina, Brigadier-General Francis of North Carolina, Captain Isaac of New Hampshire, Colonel John of Virginia, Colonel Thomas of New Hampshire, and Lieutenant William of Pennsylvania.
James, Thomas, John, Joseph, William, Edward, Jacob, Robert, and Benjamin are some of the Christian names most highly favored by the family for its male members.
A few of the many members of the family who have distinguished themselves in various parts of the world throughout the ages are:
Thomas Nash of Suffolk County, English satirist and dramatist, 1567-1601
Richard Nash, called Beau Nash, of Wales, English leader of fashion, 1674-1762
Abner Nash of Virginia, American politician, 1716-1786
Sir John Nash of London, English architect, 1752-1835; and
George Kilburn Nash of Ohio, American politician, 1842-1904.
One of the most frequently recurrent of the many coats-of-arms of the family, which is sometimes found with slight variations in coloring and detail, is described as follows:
Arms.-- Sable, on a chevron between three greyhounds statant argent, as many sprigs of ash slipped vert.
Crest.- A greyhound courant argent.
(Arms taken from Burke's General Armory, 1884.)
Nash Family History
Dwain Nash Fullerton born Oct 17 1931. Married to Patricia [UNK] Fowler July 30 1960, Pat's birthday June 30
Sarah Fullerton born Aug. 20 1964
IvanHalford Nash married Helen Melom Mar2 1935.
Their children
Martha born May 2 1938
Carl Evan Nash born May 8, 1940.
Marjorie Louise born June 17 1947
[UNK] born Jan. 22 1950
Donald O. Nash married Lorene Porter Aug 9 1930
Their children
Judith Ann born Jan. 25, 1936
Linda Rene born Oct. 24 1940
Sources
The above data have been compiled chiefly from the following sources:
S. Nash--The Nash Family, 1853.
E. T. Nash--Fifty Puritan Ancestors, 1902.
Fretz--A Genealogical Record, 1903.
Page--Page, Nash, and Peck Families, 1911.
Savage--Genealogical Dictionary of New England, 1860.
Heitman--Officers of the Continental Army, 1914.
The Americana, 1934.
Burke--General Armory, 1884, and Heraldry, 1844.
CONTAINER LIST
- 1827 - 1859 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1. [1827] Aug. 23.Erminia Nash Worcester to Erminia Nash. Family record.
  - 2. 1827, Nov. 19.Daniel Nash to Erminia Nash. Preaching, conversion and family news.
  - 3. 1831, Nov. 28.Daniel Nash to Erminia Nash. Scripture, beliefs and conversion.
  - 4. 1832, April 13.Almeda Nash to Erminia Nash (sisters). Death of father, Daniel: Dec. 20, 1831. Fragment.
  - 5. 1833, July 14 - Aug. 21.E[zra] A. Pool to Erminia Nash. Account of cholera attacks at Lane Seminary in Ohio.
  - 6. 1849, Jan. 22.Uriah and L. Church to Roxey Ann Hoagles. Family news.
  - 7. 1852, Sept. 5.Sarah B. Nash to Seymour W. Nash. Noyes, Oneida, missionary work at Newark, personal, Macknetts and fish excursion, Putney.
  - 8. 1853, Aug. 15.Sarah B. Nash to Seymour W. Nash. Mail passed at breakfast table, trip into the hills with Mallorys, whortleberry excursion, the Howards leave Oneida, John Howard, Mr. Hamilton, Atwood, Mr. Burt, Deborah, Wealthy and Russell Knowles.
  - 9. 1853, Sept. 6.Sarah B. Nash to Seymour W. Nash. Knowles family and visit of Mr. Burt and Mr. Miller, Constant Bosworth, Marther Bosworth, Betsy, Almeda and Edwin.
  - 10. 1854, March 1.W. [Atwood] Knowles to Seymour [W.] Nash. Arrival at Oneida, Mr. Burnham, Deborah.
  - 11. 1854, May 18.[Sarah B. Nash]. Harriet A. Hall, Mrs. Harriet A. Noyes, arrival of Daniel and Sophia.
  - 12. 1854, May 21.D[aniel] P[ool] Nash to Dear Friends. Sophia's health. (Died May 24)
    [UNK]
  - 13. [1854], Oct. 7.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour [W. Nash]. Personal, Brooklyn and Newark families to return to Oneida.
  - 14. 1854, Nov. 23.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Brooklyn and Newark groups coming to Oneida, Hellen [sic] Noyes, Mrs. Miller.
  - 15. 1854, Aug. 11.Oneida. S[arah] B. N[ash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal, Seymour's safe arrival, Mr. Hatch and Hial [Waters], Mr. Ackley, Ellen [Nash], Mrs. Olds, bible classes.
  - 16. 1854, Aug. 27.Oneida. Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour [W. Nash]. Mr. Noyes and Pitt to leave for Brooklyn, personal, bible game, Dr. Beach, Wealthy, Brother William, Ellen Mrs. Miller, Mrs. Sylvia Hamilton.
  - 17. [1855 or 1856], Feb.Champion. W. A.[twool] Knowles to Dear Brother [Seymour W. Nash?]. Beborah and Egbert, Edmond's death.
  - 18. 1856, June 22.Daniel P[ool] Nash to Dear Friends [Mr. and Mrs. Uriah Church]. Invitation to visit.
  - 19. 1858, Sept. 30.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Arrival in Wallingford [Sept. 23], Mr. Cragin.
  - 20. [1858?], Oct. 27.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal, S.W.N.'s visit, note on verso by Mrs. S. J. Clarke.
  - 21. [1858?], Oct. 30.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal, Mrs. Miller going to Oneida, can't go to New Haven.
  - 22. 1858, Dec. 26.Edwin S. Nash to Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church. Death of Hial Waters, Thomas & Gilbert.
  - 23. [1858?], Dec. 30.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal.
  - 24. 1859, Jan. 22.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Mr. Cragin ill, Harriet A. & Abby B.
  - 25. [1859 or later], Feb. 25.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Wallingford, personal, health, Jane Abbott and Louisa.
  - 26. 1859, Mar. 10.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal, new room, misses Mrs. Miller.
  - 27. 1859, June 19.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Visitors, Mr. Inslee, Mrs. De Wolf, picking strawberries, Mr. Thayer & Florilla.
  - 28. 1859, June 25.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal, Abby's baby, note from Ellen, strawberries.
  - 29. 1859, July 24.Seymour W. Nash to Sarah B. Nash. Personal.
  - 30. [1859, July].[Sarah B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Health, Mrs. Clark, Mrs. Hatch, Mr. Noyes to visit, Ellen.
  - 31. 1859, Nov. 27.Edwin S. Nash to Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church. Working in Buffalo, wants to be a sailor.
- 1860 - 1862 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1. 1860, Jan. 26.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal, Mrs. Clark, Mr. Ackley et al.
  - 2. 1860, Feb. 15.Sarah [B. Nash] to Seymour W. Nash. Personal, S.W.N. to visit Wallingford.
  - 3. 1861, July 5.Olive [Ann Nash] to Edwin S. Nash. Mrs. Dunn, Father, E.S.N. at New Haven.
  - 4. 1861, Oct. 7.Daniel P. Nash to [Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church]. Edwin joins Ellsworth's Regiment.
  - 5. 1861, Oct. 12.Edwin [S. Nash] to [Uriah Church]. Enlists in Ellsworth's Regiment of 44th N. Y. Volunteers, review, Peliz Cranston & Eugene Dunham, Col. Stryker, camp living.
  - 6. 1861, Nov. 17.Edwin S. Nash to Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church. Hall's Hill, Va., march from Albany, picket duty, review by Gen. McClellan.
  - 7. [1862,] Jan. 31.Edwin S. Nash to Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church. Picket duty.
  - 8. 1862, Jan. 31.Edwin S. Nash to Rillie [Florilla Nash]. Describes companions.
  - 9. 1862, Apr. 14.Edwin S. Nash to [Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church]. From Chesapeak Hospital, Ft. Monroe, Hampton. Manassas evacuated & still burning, Merimac & Monitor.
  - 10. 1862, July 14.Daniel Pool Nash to [Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church]. Sends strawberries, word from Edwin.
  - 11. 1862, July 29.Edwin S. Nash to Mr. & Mrs. Uriah Church. Wounded prisners from Richmond.
  - 12. 1862, Sept. 8.[Jennie N. Knowles] to [S. W.] Nash. Letter to and from David.
  - 13. 1862, Sept. 30.Daniel P. Nash to Uriah Church.
  - 14. [1862], Sept. 30.Edwin S. Nash to Olive Nash. Reasons for fighting.
  - 15. 1862, Oct. 3.Edwin S. Nash to Rillie [Florilla Nash]. Hospital duties and wards.
  - 16. 1862, Oct. 3.Edwin S. Nash to [Daniel P. Nash]. Emancipation Proclamation, return to Community faith.
  - 17. 1862, Oct. 22.Jennie N. Knowles to Seymour W. Nash.
  - 18. [1862], Oct. 26.Edwin S. Nash to Olive Nash. Death of Mrs. U. Church, Uncle Seymour, Aunt Sarah and Ellen.
  - 19. [1862, Oct. or Nov.].Edwin S. Nash to [Daniel P. Nash]. Grandmother's death, Circular.
  - 20. 1862, Nov. 16.Edwin S. Nash to [Florilla Nash?]. Loneliness, sick, ordered to report to regiment.
  - 21. 1862, Nov. 24.Jennie N. Knowles to Seymour W. Nash. Criticism, death of one of Seymour's children?
  - 22. 1862, Dec. 12.Jennie N. Knowles to Seymour W. Nash.
  - 23. 1862, Dec. 12.Edwin S. Nash to [Daniel P. Nash]. Opposite Fredericksburg, building pontoon bridges under fire.
  - 24. 1862, Dec. 17.Edwin S. Nash to [Daniel P. Nash]. Near Falmouth, battle of Fredericksburg, destruction.
  - 25. 1862, Dec. 27.Edwin S. Nash to Ellen [Nash]. Camp life, description, Old Point, battle, sentry duty.
- 1863 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 1. 1863, Jan. 10.Edwin S. Nash to Uriah Church. Condolence.
  - 2. 1863, Jan. 13.Erminia Nash Worcester. Abstract from a Journal. Family records, residences, assistant missionary to Cherokee Nation at Creek Path, 1831 Georgia laws imprison missionaries.
  - 3. 1863, Jan. 17.Edwin S. Nash to [Daniel Pool Nash]. Saw his letters in Circular, marching orders.
  - 4. [1863], Jan. 18.Edwin [S. Nash] to [Daniel Pool Nash]. Marching orders.
  - 5. 1863, Jan. 30.James N. Knowles To the community. Reflections on the war.
  - 6. 1863, Feb. [9].David Watson Knowles and Jennie N. Knowles to the Community.
  - 7. 1863, Feb. 12.Edwin S. Nash to [Daniel Pool Nash]. Still near Falmouth, no pay.
  - 8. 1863, Feb. 16.Edwin S. Nash to [Uriah Church]. Rest, snow storm, description of living quarters.
  - 9. 1863, Feb. 20.Edwin S. Nash to Olive Nash. Theatricals, family, Mr. Knowles' visit.
  - 10. 1863, Feb. 21.John S. Freeman to Mr. Nash.
  - 11. 1863, Mar. 1.Edwin S. Nash to Daniel P. Nash. Term of service, faith.
  - 12. 1863, Mar. 2.David Watson Knowles to the Community. Medical Director's Office, 11th Corps, Stafford Court House, Va. Gen. Sigel, account of leave.
  - 13. 1863, Mar. 3.James N. Knowles to the Community. Stafford C. H., Va., generals do not understand each other.
  - 14. [1863], Mar. 4.Edwin S. Nash to Rillie [Florilla] Nash. Rillie is 21, Burnside, improved rations.
  - 15. 1863, Mar. 7.David Watson Knowles to Seymour W. Nash. New quarters, an attempted suicide and other patients and cures.
  - 16. 1863, Mar. 7.Jennie N. Knowles to Community Friends. Husbands visit, community dress, influenza.
  - 17. 1863, Mar. 17.David Watson Knowles to [S. W.] Nash. and Community. James transferred to Baltimore.
  - 18. [1863,] Mar. 24.David Watson Knowles to [S. W.] Nash. James arrived in Baltimore, Kelly's Ford battle.
  - 19. 1863, Apr. 2.David Watson Knowles to Wallingford Community. With poem. Gen. Howard and Gen. Tambert.
  - 20. 1863, Apr. 14.Edwin S. Nash to My Dear Sister. To move.
  - 21. 1863, Apr. 14.Edwin S. Nash to [Daniel P. Nash]. Rain delays march, anticipating battle.
  - 22. 1863, May [10].Edwin S. Nash to dear Sister. Letter of May [8] (missing) to father describes battle (Fredericksburg?).
  - 23. 1863, May 10.David Watson Knowles to [S. W.] Nash et al. Account of a battle in early May, Gen. Hooker, Gordonsville, retreat, [Chancellorsville?].
  - 24. 1863, May 11.Deborah [W.] Knowles to Seymour W. Nash. Death of Docia, letter from Wealthy, Atwood, Egbert and Ellen.
  - 25. 1863, May 14.Jennie N. Knowles to Kind Friends. David safe, James' visit.
  - 26. 1863, May 20.Edwin S. Nash to Olive Ann Nash. Rappahanock R. at Kelly's Ford, van-guard, Ely's Ford and first rebels, Gen. Meade, Chancellorsville.
  - 27. 1863, May 20.A. W. Carr to Capt. [Charles W. Gibbs] of Co. J. 44th N. Y. Volunteers. Written for D. P. Nash enquiring about Edwin.
  - 28. 1863, May 26.Edwin S. Nash to Daniel P. Nash.
  - 29. 1863, May 30.Edwin S. Nash to Daniel P. Nash.
  - 30. 1863, Jun. 23-July 19.Edwin S. Nash to [Florilla Nash]. Aldie, Va., Middleburg and Ashby's Gap battle, Pierceville, Va., Battle of Gettysburgh - lost 1/3 of regiment.
  - 31. 1863, July 8.Jennie N. Knowles to S. W. Nash. Husband's leave, missed Gettysburg.
  - 32. [1863], July 24.Edwin S. Nash to Olive Ann Nash. Middleburg skirmish and Ashby's Gap, Gettysburg left flank, written near White Planes.
  - 33. [1863], Aug. 2.Edwin S. Nash to Daniel P. Nash. Warrenton, Va., problem of mail, repeat of #32, Lt. Eugene Dunham killed at Gettysburg, met D. W. Knowles.
  - 34. 1863, Aug. 30.Edwin S. Nash to Daniel P. Nash. Beverly Ford, pocket picked of $40 pay.
  - 35. 1863, Sept. 1.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Sister [Florilla Nash?]. Fragment, Beverly Ford.
  - 36. 1863, Sept. 25.Edwin S. Nash to [Olive or Ellen Nash?] Culpepper, Va., personal, meeting with D. W. Knowles, Centreville.
  - 37. 1863, Oct. 11.Edwin S. Spaulding to [Seymour and Sarah Nash?]. Impressions of newcomer to Oneida.
  - 38. 1863, Oct. 23.David Watson Knowles to Seymour W. Nash. U. S. General Hospital, Gettysburg. Jennie with him, in charge of Dispensary, summary of summer, Dr. Suckly, meeting Edwin Nash.
  - 39. 1863, Oct. 26.Jennie N. Knowles to Seymour W. Nash.
  - 40. 1863, Nov. 4.Edwin S. Nash to Olive and Ellen Nash. Near Warrenton Junction, Brandy Station.
  - 41. 1863, Nov. 15.Edwin S. Nash to Daniel P. Nash and Sisters. Kelly's Ford, Bealton.
  - 42. 1863, Nov. 24.Edwin S. Nash to My Dear Sisters. Mountain Creek, Rappahannock Station, Wilderness.
  - 43. 1863, Dec. 16.Mrs. Charlotte Augusta Miller to Seymour W. Nash. A criticism re: Louisa.
  - 44. 1863, Dec. 24.Edwin S. Nash to Daniel P. Nash. Rappahannock Station, cousin Edwin Spaulding, Oneida business prosperity and hired help, Gen. French.
  - 45. 1863, Dec. 29.Edwin S. Nash to Florilla Nash. Rappahannock Station, Leonora (child of Florilla and Cornelius Hatch?), Circular moved to Wallingford, Seymour and Sarah at Oneida, exchange of coffee & tobacco with rebels.
- 1864 - 1865 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1. 1864, Jan. 10.Edwin S. Nash to Olive Ann Nash. Personal
  - 2. 1864, Jan. 26.John S. Freeman to [S. W.] Nash. School teacher in Schnectady.
  - 3. 1864, Feb. 5.Edwin S. Nash to [Florilla Nash?]. Alexandria, train guards, activities, beliefs, meals.
  - 4. 1864, Feb. 7.David Watson Knowles to [S. W.] Nash. Annapolis, Md., consecration of Gettysburg battlefield, esteem for Lutherans.
  - 5. 1864, Feb. 28.Edwin S. Nash to [Olive Ann Nash?]. Mostly personal.
  - 6. 1864, Mar. 20.E. L. Spaulding to S. W. Nash. and Almeda [Nash] Spaulding to [S. W. Nash et al]. Edwin S. Spaulding leaves Community.
  - 7. 1864, Apr. 10.Olive Ann Nash to Seymour W. Nash. Edwin Spaulding, flower garden, Elizabeth Hawley.
  - 8. 1864, Apr. 11.David Watson Knowles to Seymour W. Nash.
  - 9. 1864, May 1.Olive Ann Nash to Seymour W. Nash. Plants arrive, etc.
  - 10. 1864, May 16.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Friends. On steamer Baltimore, Chesapeake Bay. In a battle near Richmond Wilderness, wounded & taken prisoner but re-captured, Gen. Custer.
  - 11. 1864, May 31.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Sisters. Battle at Wilderness, looses knapsack.
  - 12. [1864], May 31.Wealthy [A. Knowles] to Sarah [B. Nash]. Champion farm, Charlie, Sarah & Daty, Mercy, Charille, Hiram Knowles, Samuel, Atwood, Spauldings leave, Russel, Deborah, Edmund dead?, Volucia, William and Emily.
  - 13. 1864, June 7.David Watson Knowles to S. W. Nash. Gettysburg relics, fans, debris, making fans, Jennie in N. Y. and Conn., Gen. Grant.
  - 14. [1864, June 12](begun May 26). Edwin S. Nash to Dear Friends. Battle of the Wilderness, hit by a stray shot, captured.
  - 15. a 1864, June 12.(begun earlier). Edwin S. Nash to Dear Friends. Captured, Gen. Law's HQs, trading with captors, no food, Beaver Dam Station, re-taken by Gen. Custer (description), Gen. Sheridan. Fragment.
  - 16.a 1864, June 24.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Sisters. Petersburg, burns old letters, man wounded as he writes, personal.
  - 17.a 1864, July 2.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Friends. Petersburg, opinion of Confederacy & Confederates, soldiers are children & old men in last army, desertions, Old Church, Chickahominy.
  - 18. [1864], July 10.Edwin S. Nash to Olive Ann Nash. Heat, flowers and plants, personal.
  - 19.a [1864], July 11.Edwin S. Nash to Rillie [Florilla Nash]. Independence Day.
  - 20.a 1864, July 25.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Friends. Siege of Petersburg, trenches.
    [UNK] [UNK] 20d 20e.
  - 21. 1864, Sept. 18.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Sisters. Six Mile Station, term ends the 24th.
  - 22. 1864, Oct. 2.Wealthy A. Knowles to [Sarah B. Nash?]. Trip hom, Deborah ill, letter from Edmund Spaulding, Egbert Knowles.
  - 23.a 1864, Oct. 2.Edwin S. Nash to Dear Sisters. Albany, to be mustered out this week.
    [UNK] [UNK] [UNK] [UNK] [UNK] [UNK]
  - 24.a [1864].Edwin S. Nash to [Sisters]. Fragment, 3 months to end of term.
    1/2 1/22 [UNK] [UNK]
  - 25. 1865, Jan. 27.W. Atwood Knowles to [Seymour W. Nash]. Sorry he left Community & wishes to return.
  - 26. 1865, Jan. 29.John Humphrey Noyes to [Peggy Noyes]., A copy.
  - 27.[UNK] 1865, Jan. 29.Wealthy A. Knowles to Sarah B. Nash. Family news.
  - 28. 1865, Mar. 2.Rillie [Florilla Nash] to Edwin S. Nash. She is 23, personal.
    2/4 [UNK]
  - 29. 1865, Apr. 23.Wealthy A. Knowles to [Sarah B. Nash]. Family news.
  - 30. 1865, Apr. 24.W. Atwood Knowles to Seymour W. Nash. Money for Community.
  - 31. 1865, May 28.John S. Freeman to [Seymour W. Nash]. Theology.
  - 32. 1865, June 28.John S. Freeman to [Seymour W. Nash].
  - 33. 1865, Aug. 29.Rillie [Florilla Nash] to Edwin S. Nash. Olive to join Edwin in the Office.
    sept. 65
  - 34. 1865, Oct. 1.Wealthy A. Knowles to Sarah & Seymour Nash. Family news, Egbert's marriage, Daty is 14.
  - 35. 1865, Oct. 31.John S. Freeman to [S. W. Nash]. Dr. Hickok, college, equal suffrage, eight-hour system brother Charles.
  - 36. 1865.Wealthy A. Knowles to [Sarah B. Nash]. Deborah prejudiced against Seymour, personal & family.
- 1866 - 1869 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1. 1866, Jan. 3.[Florilla Nash] to Edwin S. Nash. Personal and family.